A Guide to the Papers of Paul T. David 1936-1939
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Paul T. David 1936-1939
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12793-i
This collection consists of ca. 1000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the University of Virginia Library as a gift on August 30, 1999.
Biographical/Historical Information
Economist, government official, University of Virginia Professor of Government and Foreign Affairs, author.
Scope and Content Information
The collection consists chiefly of papers relating to David's employment with the Tennessee Valley Authority and the American Federation of Government Employees, including annual reports, circulars, clippings, correspondence, manuals, memoranda, newsletters and miscellaneous printed items.
Topics include pertinent Civil Service legislation particularly the Sirovich Bill and McKellar rider; disputes with A.F.G.E. national president E. Claude Babcock; personnel issues at T.V.A. particularly employee relations and salaries; and presidency of T.V.A. Lodge #136.
Correspondents include Paul A. Strachan and Robert Ramspeck.
Contents List
- American Federation of Government Employee Papers
  - E. Claude Babcock, National President 1935-1936 (Box 1)
  - Constitution and By-Laws 1932-1935 (Box 1)
  - Conventions 1934-1935 (Box 1)
  - Paul T. David 1934-1936 (Box 1)
  - Educational Activities 1935 (Box 1)
  - Employee Relations Policy 1935 (Box 1)
  - Executive Council 1935 (Box 1)
  - Federal Employees Relations Course 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - Legislation- McKellar Rider 1934-193[?] (Box 1)
  - Legislation- Sirovich Bill 1935 (Box 1)
  - Legislation Pending 1935 (Box 1)
  - Lodges 1934-1935, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Newsclippings 1935-1936 (Box 2)
  - Esther Penn, National Secretary 1934-1935 (Box 2)
  - Paul A. Strachan 1934-1937, 5 folders (Box 2)
  - United Front for Better Government Personnel 1935 (Box 2)
- Tennessee Valley Authority Papers
  - Hydro Electric Power Commission of Ontario 1934-1935 (Box 3)
  - Hydro Electric Power Commission of Ontario: Propaganda Career of Samuel S. Wyer 1925-1934 (Box 3)
  - Annual Reports 1934-1936, Printed, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Annual Report of the Board-Preparation of the First 1934-1936 (Box 3)
  - Annual Report of the Board-Appraisal on the Second 1935-1938 (Box 3)
  - A Chronology 1933 (Box 3)
  - Newsclippings 1934-1937 (Box 3)
  - Organization Manuals 1936, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Personnel-Civil Service Legislation 1935-1937 (Box 4)
  - Personnel-Employee Relations 1936-1943, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Personnel-Employee Relations 1940-1943, Printed, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Personnel-Salary Plan 1936 (Box 4)
  - Personnel-Salary Study 1933-1937, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Personnel-Training 1938, 1944, Printed (Box 4)
  - Personnel-Unemployment Compensation 1936 (Box 4)
  - Planning-Place of Regional Planning in the Nation 1933-1935 (Box 5)
  - Planning-Relationship of Land Planning Division to other planning divisions 1935 (Box 5)
  - Planning-Working Plan 1935 (Box 5)
  - Public Works 1935 (Box 5)
  - Real Estate Reports 1928-1933 (Box 5)
  - Tennessee River System 1933-1936, Printed (Box 5)
  - The TVA Standard 1935 (Box 5)
  - Transport Aviation 1930-1934 (Box 5)
  - United States Department of Agriculture: Report of the Director of Personnel 1940-1942 (Box 5)
  - United States Civil Service Commission: Paul T. David Application for Principal Economist 1940-1941 (Box 5)
  - WCOY Broadcasting, a skit presented at the Bureau of the Budget dinner 1944 (Box 5)
  - Writings of Paul T. David 1936-1942, 1962, Printed (Box 5)